Finding Aid for American Legion, Dept. of Michigan records, 1919-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Cancelled Post Files, 1919-1999
  - Plymouth
    - #232-Scott D. Courtwrite (Box 15)
  - Pontiac
    - #311-John Baynard (African American) (Box 15)
    - #411-Wells-Edwards Post (Box 15)
    - #437-Wilson Foundry Post (Box 15)
    - #466-Tobin-Cote (Box 15)
  - Port Austin
    - #341-Brown (Box 15)
  - Port Huron
    - #393-Charles Thompson (Box 16)
    - #400-Francis G. Hayes (Box 16)
  - Potterville
    - #288-Potterville (Box 16)
  - Prescott
    - #358-Roy Henry (Box 16)
  - Ramsay
    - #350-Fredrickson-Torreano (Box 16)
  - Reese
    - #340-Moquin-Nichols (Box 16)
  - Remus
    - #446-Carl H. Taylor Post (Box 16)
  - Republic
    - #290-Goodney-Johnson-Isaacson (Box 16)
  - Richmond
    - #125-Sullivan-Burke (Box 16)
  - River Rouge
    - #84-Young-Valois-Palmer (African American) (Box 16)
    - #314-Wallis-Wainwright-Hack (Box 16)
  - Rockwood
    - #441-Zimmer-Giffin-Forest (Box 16)
  - Romeo
    - #109-Vern Hilliker (Box 16)
  - Roscommon
    - #326-Roscommon (Box 16)
  - Rose City
    - #209-Bechraft-Nichols (Box 16)
  - Roseville
    - #381-Roseville (Box 16)
  - Rothbury
    - #467-Thomas Patrick Reavey Post (Box 16)
  - Royal Oak Township
    - #288-Madison (Box 16)
    - #448-Watkins-Byrd-Simmons Post (African American) (Box 16)
  - Rudyard
    - #307-Enslish Berkompas (Box 16)
    - #316-Frank R. Maki (Box 16)
  - Saginaw
    - #312-Albert Davis Vernon (African American) (Box 16)
    - #544-Aleda Lutz (Box 16)
  - St. Clair
    - #143-Charles J. Fulton (Box 16)
    - #477-John W. Hazard (Box 16)
  - St. Charles
    - #218-Water (Box 16)
  - St. Joseph
    - #299-Riverview (Box 16)
  - Sandusky
    - #219-Russell J. Wakefield (Box 16)
  - Sand Lake
    - #212-Huff-Tracy (Box 16)
  - Scottville
    - #156-Scottville (Box 16)
    - #156-Samuel Shunk (Box 16)
  - Shepherd
    - #191-Roy H. Spink (Box 16)
  - Sherwood
    - #482-Sherwood Post (Box 16)
  - Southfield Township
    - #407-Southfield Post (Box 16)
  - Snover
    - #231-John Adair (Box 16)
  - Stanwood
    - #1993-Altona American Legion (Box 16)
  - South Lyon
    - #560-Tri-County Post (Box 16)
  - Springport
    - #306-Paul E. Steffe (Box 16)
  - Stanton
    - #134-Clevenger Buskirk (Box 16)
  - Stockbridge
    - #116-J. T. Glenn (Box 16)
  - Sumpter Township
    - #395-Sumpter Post (Box 16)
  - Sunfield
    - #257-Ora V. Church (Box 16)
  - Taylor Township
    - #402-Taylor Center (Box 16)
  - Tekonsha
    - #118-Eldredge King Post (Box 16)
    - #527-Eldredge King Post (Box 16)
  - Trenary
    - #511-Howard Tweedale (Box 16)
  - Trenton
    - #351-Alfred Fuller (Box 16)
  - Tustin
    - #209-Arthur C. Larson (Box 16)
  - Twining
    - #369-Viele Memorial (Box 16)
  - Twin Lake
    - #278-Wm. Patelski (Box 16)
  - Ubly
    - #330-Smith-Delleree (Box 16)
  - Union City
    - #196-Union Post (Box 16)
  - Utica
    - #193-Victor I. Rieck (Box 16)
  - Vanderbilt
    - #77-John Mertin Brodie (Box 16)
  - Van Dyke
    - #306-Van Dyke (Box 16)
  - Vassar
    - #177-Atkinson (Box 16)
  - Vestaburg
    - #260-Frank White (Box 16)
  - Walloon Lake
    - #541-Dean S. Scroggie Post (Box 16)
  - Warren
    - #114-Warren (Box 16)
    - #401-Walter O. Briggs (Box 16)
  - Waterford
    - #431-Waterford Township Post (Box 16)
  - Watersmeet
    - #70-John Wenz (Box 16)
  - Watervliet
    - #338-Watervliet-Coloma (Box 16)
  - Weidman
    - #343-Howard Nichols (Box 16)
  - White Cloud
    - #99-White Cloud (Box 16)
  - Whittemore
    - #490-Dorsey Post (Box 16)
  - Willow Run
    - #412-Kaiser-Frazer Post (Box 16)
  - Woodhaven
    - #224-Woodhaven (Box 16)
  - Ypsilanti
    - #379-Willow Lodge (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous Posts (Box 16)
- Other Records 1926-1999
  Other Records (1926-1999, 1 linear foot) consist of the constitution and by-laws of the American Legion, records pertaining to the American Legion Hospital in Battle Creek, MI, information on the various scholarships and trusts offered by the Michigan department, and records and publications tracing both the history of the Michigan department's headquarters and the history of the American Legion in general.
  - Constitution and By-Laws
    - 1926-1975 (Box 17)
    - 1976-1982 (Box 17)
    - 1986-1998 (Box 17)
  - Amendments to Constitution
    - 1967-1984 (Box 17)
    - 1985-1999 (Box 17)
  - American Legion Hospital
    - Constitution (Box 17)
    - Legal Documents (Box 17)
    - Financial Documents, Reports (Box 17)
    - Reports, Correspondence Photographs (Box 17)
    - Planned Living Center (Legion Villa) (Box 17)
  - Scholarships and Trusts
    - Brewer Trust
      - Legal Documents (Box 17)
      - Account Statements (Box 17)
    - William Morris Scholarship (Box 17)
    - Trust Account Summaries (Box 17)
  - Historical Documents
    - Michigan Department Headquarters History (Box 17)
    - Publications (Box 17)
- Otter Lake Children's Billet 1919-1970s
  The records of the Otter Lake Children's Billet (1926-1970s, 1 linear foot) include meeting minutes of the billet board and other committees, various documents detailing the operation of the facility, legal documentation, photographs, reports and press releases.
  - Billet Board Minutes
    - December 1926-June 1931 (Box 18)
    - February 1933-August 1944 (Box 18)
    - December 1944-December 1949 (Box 18)
    - June 1952-December 1955 (Box 18)
    - January 1950-August 1969 (include miscellaneous) (Box 18)
  - Billet Committee Minutes
    - October 12, 1952 (Box 18)
    - October 1954-July 1957 (Box 18)
  - Children's Home Committee Minutes July 1958-December 1965 (Box 18)
  - Appropriation Requests and Inventories 1954-1957 (Box 18)
  - Physical Specifications (Box 18)
  - Reports, Press Releases Photographs (Box 18)
  - Survey Report January 1956 (Box 18)
  - Statement of Policy and Operations Manual (Box 18)
  - Legal Documentation (Box 18)
- Scrapbooks/Photograph Albums 1898-1970
  The Scrapbooks and Photograph Albums (1898-1970, 8 oversize volumes) series details Legion conventions, photographs of meetings and other gatherings, community service projects, and assorted newspaper clippings.
  - Loose items from scrapbooks
    - Portraits and Group Photographs 1940s (Box 18)
      (From Oversize Vol. 7)
    - Newspapers detailing convention activities 1931 (Folder 1)
      (From Oversize Vol. 6)
    - Photographic Portraits of National Commanders 1946-1949 (Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings concerning the American Legion Junior Baseball Program 1963 (Folder 1)
    - Poster chronicling the presidents of the American Legion Auxiliary (Folder 1)
      (From Oversize Vol. 8)
  - Newspaper clippings, including obituaries, fictional serials, and national and international news 1898-1915 (Volume 1)
  - Newspaper clippings detailing the annual convention 1930-1931 (Volume 6)
  - Newspaper clippings detailing the annual convention and other legion business 1931-1940 (Volume 2)
  - Portraits and group photographs from meetings, conventions, banquets, etc. Late 1930s-Late 1950s (Volume 7)
  - Hometown U.S.A., project scrapbook regarding a legion program focused on sending recorded messages to servicemen overseas 1953 (Volume 3)
  - Scrapbook & Photographs, consisting of newspaper clippings relating Legion events and news, and group photographs 1956-1966 (Volume 4)
  - Public Relations, project scrapbook concerning efforts to educate the public in regard to Legion programs, as well as for internal education 1965-1969 (Volume 5)
  - Legion Publications, consisting primarily of selections from the Wolverine Auxiliary and the Michigan Legionnaire 1965-1970 (Volume 8)
- Sound Recording 1953
  Finally, there is a Sound Recording (1953, 1 vinyl record) linked to the Hometown USA scrapbook, which was a project involving sending recorded messages to servicemen overseas.
  - Hometown U.S.A. November 4, 1953 (Box 1)